Descendants: The Royal Wedding is a animation, family,
comedy film directed by Salvador Simó.
Happily-ever-after continues for Auradon's power couple as they prepare to say "I do" at an epic
celebration with their friends and family, but Hades threatens to ruin it all.
Mal (voice), played by Dove Cameron.
Evie (voice), played by Sofia Carson.
Jay (voice), played by Booboo Stewart.
Ben (voice), played by Mitchell Hope.
Audrey (voice), played by Sarah Jeffery.
Fairy Godmother (voice), played by Melanie Paxson.
Descendants is an American media franchise centered on a
series of Disney Channel musical fantasy films.
The franchise was created by Josann McGibbon and Sara Parriott, with the first three films directed by
Kenny Ortega, the fourth directed by Jennifer Phang, and the fifth directed by Kimmy Gatewood.
The Descendants franchise is set in a universe that continues the
narratives of Disney's animated classic films.
The series stars Dove Cameron, Cameron Boyce, Sofia Carson, and Booboo Stewart, and each film follows the
lives of the teenage children of four Disney Villains who reside on the Isle of the Lost.
They are invited to the kingdom of Auradon by the
teenage son of Queen Belle and King Beast.
The first film premiered as a Disney Channel Original Movie in July 2015.
Due to its success, a sequel was produced and premiered
across six Disney-owned networks in July 2017.
The third film debuted on Disney Channel in August 2019.
A spinoff film to the previous three, Descendants: The Rise of Red, starring Kylie Cantrall and Malia Baker, was released on Disney+ on
July 12, 2024, which will be followed by a sequel, Descendants: Wicked Wonderland, scheduled to be released in summer 2026.
The film series also led to the creation of several television
series, short films, television specials, and novels.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.